John Wei Kang ONG Mobile: +65 8223 5074

Email: weikang.ong@u.nus.edu Skype: ongwk95@hotmail.com

Online Resume: https://johnweikangong.github.io/



Personal Statement

About me

As an avid programmer and major in computer engineering, I hope to propel innovation to improve the lives of all. To reach this aspiration, I have participated in multiple events and hackathons, honing my skills and social connectivity in the process. One experience that resonates with me was the Startup Weekend Singapore Mega, at which teams turned ideas into startups within 54 hours. My team developed a location-based application prototype for users with similar interests to mingle, with venue optimization as our core business model. This gave me first-hand experience of the stages of a startup and it was certainly an eye-opening experience for me. Optimism is key, and I believe that possessing this as well as determination, I will be able to make a difference.

How I can contribute

I am eager to contribute with my abilities. I have taken foundation courses in my university that taught me C and Java programming language. As part of a software engineering project, I led a team of computing students to develop a full featured address book written in Java.

Additionally, I possess web development experience. In my recent internship at Manifera Software Development Private Limited, I led a team of 7 engineers to develop an inventory management system for the KK Women's and Children's Hospital in Singapore. Above that, I developed the web-based inventory management application using the MEAN framework, which interacts with the hardware sensors to provide a seamless real-time monitoring system. Developing the whole concept from ideation to a sustainable business model, it is without a doubt an enriching experience.

Furthermore, I have experience in the development of Android and Unity. I co-developed an Android game application using the Unity game engine as part of an independent and self-directed project. The potato-themed game encourages interaction amongst users to help break down social barriers during gatherings. With no prior experience, I managed to acquire and master the basics of Unity in a week and finished the product in 3 months. Besides my technical skills, I am willing to diversify into unchartered areas and learn new skillsets that the company would require from me.

Why me

My strong communication skills have put me in good stead in working with a team. Many of the courses I took have placed strong emphasis on professional communication. I am confident in communicating clearly with people from diverse backgrounds and building good relationships. Apart from that, I can manage my time well. In the recent internship with Manifera, I was given weekly deadlines. As the lead intern, I set clear goals to ensure every deadline was met satisfactorily with no compromise made. Moreover, I am a strongly independent person. Having served in the military for two years, it has taught me to take ownership of my own work and adapt quickly to changing situations and foreign environments. With these, I believe that I will be an asset to your organization.

Education

Aug 2016 - Present National University of Singapore

Bachelor of Computing (Honors) in Computer Engineering

(Course details in Appendix A)

Jan 2012 - Dec 2013

Anderson Junior College

• Singapore-Cambridge General Certificate of Education Advanced Level

Work Experience

May 2017 – Aug 2017

Manifera Software Development Private Limited

Lead Software Development Intern

- Led a team of 7 engineers to develop an inventory management system for the KK Women's and Children's Hospital in Singapore
- Developed the web-based management application using the MEAN framework
- Integrated hardware sensors and software for a seamless real-time monitoring system

Feb 2014 - Jun 2016

42nd Battalion, Singapore Armored Regiment

Section Commander

- Led a platoon of 30 men through rigorous trainings
- Awarded Best Commander Award for display of dedication and leadership
- Promoted as an Armor Driving Instructor, assessing and qualifying soldiers on armored platforms

Scholastic Achievements/Extracurricular Activities

Sep 2017 – Oct 2017

Startup Weekend Singapore Mega

- Led a team of 7 participants in transforming an idea into a startup within 54 hours
- Developed a location-based application prototype for users with similar interest to mingle, with venue optimization as our core business model

May 2017 - Aug 2017

Android Game Project

• Co-developed an Android game application using the Unity game engine as part of an independent and self-directed project

Jan 2017 - Feb 2017

IDEa\$ Challenge Hackathon

- Led a team of 4 freshmen across engineering and business faculties to develop and pitch an idea based on a campus's need
- Developed a seat management system using the Arduino to solve the problem of seat-hogging in libraries
- Awarded Best Participants Award

Jan 2012 - Dec 2013

Anderson Junior College

- Awarded College Class Leader Award for recognition of contributions to college activities
- Awarded Platinum Social Service Award for contributing more than 300 hours of community service

Skill Sets & Proficiency

Programming	Java C C#	Proficient Intermediate Basic
Web	HTML CSS JavaScript Node.js jQuery Angular.js Express.js	Intermediate Intermediate Proficient Intermediate Intermediate Intermediate Intermediate Intermediate
Database	MongoDB (NoSQL)	Intermediate
Game Engine	Unity	Intermediate
Integrated Development Environment	IntelliJ Atom Eclipse	Proficient Proficient Intermediate
Server Management & Network	Server Setup/Maintenance	Basic
Version Control Tools	Git	Intermediate
Hardware Design	HDL (Verilog) Arduino prototyping Circuit design	Proficient Proficient Basic
Operating Systems	Windows XP, 7, 10	Proficient
Non-technical Skills	Project Management	Proficient
Language Proficiency		

Spoken Written $English-Fluent;\,Mandarin-Fluent$ English – Competent; Chinese – Average

Degree: Bachelor of Computing (Honors) in Computer Engineering

Cumulative Average Point: 4.24 / 5.00

Classification	Course Name	Grades
Software Development	Introduction to Computer Engineering	A-
	Programming Methodology	B+
	Data Structures and Algorithms I	S
	Discrete Structures	S
	Software Engineering	IP
	Real-Time Operating Systems	IP
	Computational Thinking	IP
	Independent Software Development Project	CS
Hardware Development	Electrical Engineering	B+
	Devices & Circuits	A-
	Digital Fundamentals	IP
Communication Skills	Critical Thinking & Writing	B+
	Effective Communication for Computing Professionals	IP
Foundations	Introduction to Design Thinking	B+
	Mathematics I	A-
	Mathematics II	A-
	Physics IIE	A-

NUS Grading Scale:

A+ & A (5.0); A- (4.5); B+ (4.0); B (3.5); B- (3.0); C+ (2.5); C (2.0); D+ (1.5); D (1.0); F (0)

S = Satisfactory; U = Unsatisfactory

CS = Completed Satisfactorily; CU = Completed Unsatisfactorily

EXE = Exempted; IC = Incomplete; IP = In Progress; W = Withdrawn